So, you're saying that one of them is Kira, right?
その中の一人が…キラなんですね
Yes, and I've got plenty of proof.
はい、証拠はたくさんあるんです
The victim was Mr. "H".
犠牲になったのは、 H さんです
エイチ
Soon Kira's identity will become clear!
キラの正体は、番組の最後に！
If Higuchi is similar to the second Kira and can kill someone solely by knowing their face, Matsuda-san will die.
もし火口が第二のキラの様に、顔だけで殺せることがあれば…
松田さんが死にます
I-It's him?!
あ…あいつだ！
Don't fuck with me! You should at least know the names of your employees!
ふざけるな！
雇った人間の名前ぐらい、覚えておけ！
I've still got two hours...
まだ二時間ある…
火口確認
Higuchi's status confirmed.
所持品はバックのみ、追います
He's got a bag with him.
I'm in pursuit.
必ず、殺してやる…
I'll kill him for sure...
I'm going to have it all!
俺は…全てを手に入れるんだ！
Frenzy
Cosme Misa
Cosme Misa.
Brilliant gloss.
小悪魔の艶
天使の輝き
The sparkle of an angel.
Misa ☆の勝ち組ルージュ　発進
Misa's Cashmere Rouge.
The commercials are ending, Ryuuzaki.
もう CM が終わるが、竜崎
Is that so?
そうですか
I ended up drinking with the eight of them, including Kira.
それで、キラを含め八人と酒を飲むことになったんです
はは…それは面白い
That's fascinating.
I can't say any more right now, or those who were present at the time might figure out who Kira is.
あまり詳しいことを言うと、
その場にいた人達に誰がキラだったのかわかってしまうので
これ以上、今は言えませんけどね
はい、誰がキラなのか、この先ゆっくりとお願いします
Of course. Please take your time and reveal Kira's identity when you're ready.
Please set the channels so Audio One is streaming from Higuchi's car and Audio Two from Sakura TV.
音声１は火口の車内、２はさくらテレビでお願いします
やはり火口…車の中でもしっかりテレビを観ているな
It's as we thought. Higuchi's making sure to watch the TV even from his car.
Going back to what you said earlier, have you actually met Kira in the flesh?
先程の話ですと、キラと対面したということですが…
Yes, although at the time, I hadn't realized who Kira was.
はい
その時は誰がキラなのかはわかってなかったんですけど
However, I think it's really brave of you to come onto the show, considering that Kira has seen your face.
しかし、顔を見られていながら、
こうして出演するのは、勇気ある行動とは思いますが…
Are you okay with this?
大丈夫ですか？
Yes. While I was investigating, I discovered that Kira needs two things in order to kill.
はい
私は調べるうちに、キラが人を殺すのに、
必要なものは、二つあるとわかりました
I know there are a lot of rumors around this topic, but I've figured it out.
それが何なのか噂は色々ありますが、
私は、はっきりわかったんです
A face... and a name...
顔と…名前……
But in my case, Kira doesn't know my name.
しかしキラは私に関して、そのうち片方を知りません
So, he's doing this because he thinks that I won't be able to kill him as I don't know his real name, eh?
本名がバレてないから、
殺されないと思って出てきたという事か
Does this mean that he's destroyed all evidence of his real name?
だとすれば、名前に繋がる物は残さない…
If he's thought as far ahead as destroying his old records... even if I went to Yoshida Productions...
履歴書まで頭が回っていれば、ヨシダプロに行っても…
Rem, what do you think?
レム、どう思う？
Think? About what?
ん？
「どう」って何がだ？
レム…誰だ？
"Rem"? Who's that? He got into the car alone...
車には一人で乗り込んでいるし、
あの車に他の者がいるとは思えない
I can't believe that there would be someone else in there with him.
He's not using a cell phone either... maybe he's using a radio or something?
携帯も使っていない…
無線か何かか？
No, there's no radio in that car. Only our bugging devices, cameras and transmitters.
いえ、あの車には無線はついていません
こっちの盗聴器、カメラ、発信器だけです
No, there's no radio in that car. Only our bugging devices, cameras and transmitters.
ウエディの仕事なので確かです
I'm certain because Weddy placed those devices there.
Even if I go to Yoshida Productions, there's a chance that there won't be any records...
ヨシダプロに行っても、履歴書なんかないんじゃないのか
Is he talking to himself?
独り言か？
Why are you asking me? How should I know?
そんなこと…私に聞かれてもわかるわけないだろ
切れる奴なら、
自分の名前に繋がる物は、全て始末してからテレビに出る…
If he's smart, he'd have destroyed any evidence of his real name before going on TV.
Besides, isn't it a little careless of Yoshida Productions to allow me to just waltz in and look for it myself?
それに、ヨシダプロの「勝手に事務所に入って見てくれ」
というのも、無用心じゃないか？
いや…この場合、盗難が遭っても、
犯人は私だということにしかならないか…
Then again, as the only person who was there, I guess I'll be held accountable if anything is stolen.
Somehow, this doesn't look good...
なんかまずいんじゃない？
It's okay. He'll go.
大丈夫です
必ず行きます
Even if the records are at Yoshida Productions, it could just be another false name... then what?!
ヨシダプロに履歴書があっても、それも偽名だったらどうだ？
I'm guessing in this kind of situation, it's highly likely that he has gone that far.
いや…この場合そこまであいつがしている可能性は、大いにある
I'm guessing it's Light and Misa's plan for him to go to Yoshida Productions...
多分火口をヨシダプロに行かせるのが、
月や海砂の策なのだろう…
But he knows you're Kira, and if things continue as they are, he'll reveal your name.
しかしこのままだと、あいつがお前をキラだと知っているなら
お前の名前が発表される
Those are the facts.
それも事実だ
There's less than an hour before the big announcement!
さあ、いよいよ発表まで１時間を切りました
All you can do now is to go and take a look.
行ってみるしかないだろう
履歴書の名前が偽名だろうがそうでなかろうが
Regardless of whether the name on the record is fake or not,
there's no way anyone would suspect you of killing people by using a notebook.
ノートによる殺人でお前が怪しまれることはない
Yeah, I get all that.
ああ、そんなことはわかってる
But to be on the safe side,
しかし念のためその後、
電話してしまったヨシダプロの者
it would be best if I killed everyone that I've talked to at Yoshida Productions, as well as Misa and her manager.
海砂やマネージャーは、殺しておいた方がいいな
Wha--?! No! He's going to kill me?!
えっ！…やだ、殺すって…
Stop panicking. He's talking about after he's killed Matsuda-san.
大丈夫です
松田さんを殺したらという意味の「その後」です
Unless he kills Matsuda-san, there would be no point in him doing that.
松田さんを殺せなければ、それをやる意味はありません
You're right, but...
確かにそうだが…
Think carefully. He's the only one you need to kill.
よく考えろ
あいつを殺すだけでいい
If you start killing those you called earlier, your call records will make you look suspicious.
さっき電話した人間たちを殺せば、
通信記録からお前が怪しまれる
That's true... you're pretty smart, Rem.
そうか…
レム、お前、頭いいな…
Then I'll just manipulate them to delete all their incoming call records before I kill them.
では、操って着信履歴を消させて殺す…
However, the phone company's records will still remain.
しかし電話会社の方の記録は残るぞ
やはり独り言とは思えない…
There's no way he's talking to himself!
レムって誰だ…
Who is this "Rem"? Who is he talking to?!
誰と話している…
もしあそこで会話しているのなら…
If he's really having a conversation with someone, it's with... a Shinigami... perhaps?
死神
うわっ…
If he's really having a conversation with someone, it's with... a Shinigami... perhaps?
ですかね～？
With someone like this, maybe I should act first...
こいつなら、こっちから先に…
How about you return the ownership of the notebook to me?
ノートの所有権を私に返すのはどうだ？
No, all that means is that I'll end up with a pitiful end.
いや、そんな事をしても、惨めな末路しかない
He says that he's got proof.
あいつは証拠もあると言っている…
Plus if they compare Yotsuba's growth against the deaths that have occurred, no one is going to doubt his story.
それに、ヨツバの成長と照らし合わせたら
あいつの言ってる事も真実だと、誰も疑わなくなるだろう…
Anybody he says is Kira will be labeled Kira for life.
あいつが喋ったキラは、キラにされる
Even if they don't find any hard evidence... my life will be over.
もし、明白な証拠が出なかったとしても、俺の人生は終わる…
Forget about promotions, I probably won't even be allowed to stay at Yotsuba.
出世どころか、ヨツバには居られなくなるだろう
Of course, our staff on this show have structured the program with the assumption that Kira will be watching.
もちろん、我々スタッフは、
「キラもこの番組を観ている」
とそう想定して、番組を構成しています
Then, I'd like to address Kira directly...
じゃあ、キラに呼びかけますよ
Kira! Turn yourself in!
キラ、自首しなさい
He pretends to be an idiot, but that night he managed to fake his own death to stay alive.
こいつ、馬鹿な振りをしているが
あの時も死んだ様に見せかけて死を逃れた…
Whatever happens, I must kill him.
とにかく殺さなければ…
Higuchi has arrived at Yoshida Productions.
火口はヨシダプロについた…
Here we go...
いよいよですね
Left as you enter...
入って左の…
The desk right at the far end...
奥の机の…
In the very bottom drawer...
一番下の引き出し…
Manager
Yamashita Yaichirou
So, how are you going to kill him? Show me!
さあ、どうやって殺すんだ…
見せてみろ！
We're prepared to apprehend Higuchi the moment you give us the signal.
火口を押さえる用意はできています
いつでも指示を
Okay.
はい
Yamashita Taichirou
It's no use! All he's done is make a note of the name, and now he's leaving!
ダメだ！
名前をメモしただけで出るぞ
ここでは殺さないのか？
He's not going to kill him here?
竜崎…押さえますか？
Ryuuzaki, should I apprehend him?
We've yet to confirm how he kills.
まだ殺し方が判明していません
He might do something once he gets back in his car.
もしかしたら、車内で何かをするのかもしれません
Bring up the inside of Higuchi's car on monitor one.
モニター位置を火口の車内へ
Higuchi seems surprisingly calm for someone who desperately wants Matsuda-san to be dead.
一秒でも早く、松田さんを殺したいはずなのに…
冷静だな火口は
True... and if he needed the name, he could have taken the records with him instead of putting them back.
そうですね
名前が必要なら、履歴書ごとも出てればいいものを
履歴書を引き出しに戻した…
36... 37... 38... 39... 40 seconds.
３６…
３７…
36... 37... 38... 39... 40 seconds.
３８…
３９…
36... 37... 38... 39... 40 seconds.
４０秒…
キラは殺人犯ですから、私は絶対に許しません
Kira is a murderer! I'll never forgive him!
Shit, he won't die!!
くそっ！死なない！
What does he mean by that?! "He won't die"?
…どういうことだ!?
「死なない」って言ったぞ
もう殺しの作業をしたのか…
He's already attempted to kill him?
名前を書くことが殺しの行動なのか
Could writing down their name be how he kills?
どうするんだ？
What should we do? Wait and see what he does?
まだ泳がせて観るのか？
I can only assume it means he can kill someone merely by knowing their name and wanting them to die.
やはり…名前だけで「死ね」と思えば、殺せるとしか…
What's going on? I can't determine how he's killing people.
どうなってる…
しかし殺し方が判定できない…
ここで押さえて自白を取ろうとしても、また…
If we apprehend him now and attempt to force a confession out, once again he'll...
There are 50 minutes left until the Kira announcement!
キラ発表まで、あと５０分！
Damn it! There's no time left!
くそっ…もう時間がない
He's calling someone.
電話を掛けている…
Most likely Misa-san again.
また海砂さんでしょう
Bingo!
当たり
おい～～～～！！
顔はわかっているんだ…
I know what he looks like...
会社に行けば、あいつ忍び込んだ時の監視ビデオテープがある
If I go to the office, there'll be security tapes of that time he snuck in...
If I had the eyes of a Shinigami...
死神の目があれば…
Half my life span, eh?
残りの寿命の半分か…
But if he does reveal my name, my life's as good as over anyways.
しかし…発表されれば、私の人生は終わるも同然…
ならば、太く短く…
Then, I may as well live a short but fulfilled life.
Rem, it's time to do the deal.
レム、取引だ
"Deal"? Who is this "Rem" he keeps talking about?
取引…!?
何ださっきから言っている「レム」って…
Is Kira's power really something that's bestowed from above?
本当にキラの力は、天から何かのものなのか
I wouldn't like to think so.
それは考えたくないですね
In that case, what the hell is "Rem"?
じゃあレムって何だ？
A Shinigami?
死神…
Either way, I think we should continue observing him.
とにかく、様子を見たほうがいいですね
まだいろいろ出てきそうですし
We could learn a lot.
We may even discover how he kills.
殺し方もはっきりするかもしれません
Now I really am invincible!
これで俺は最強だ
これならいくらでも手はある
Now I'll always have a trick up my sleeve.
We're going after him.
追います！
You in the Porsche! Stop!
そこのポルシェ、止まりなさい
Pull over to the side! Stop the car!
道路脇に寄せ、止まりなさい
ちっ…
Bad news. He's been pulled over by a patrol bike.
まずいわね
火口が白バイに捕まった
I'll have to go past him. I'm leaving the rest to you and Aiber.
私はやり過ごすので、アイバーたちお願い
You were speeding. Let's see your license.
スピード違反だ、免許証
ああ、わかったよ
Ah, alright.
全画面、火口の車内に
Show me the inside of Higuchi's car on full screen.
I wonder where I put my license...
免許証どこに入れたかな…
I don't have time for this!
こんなのに付き合ってる暇はない
The name "Shiroba Ito" is a pun. "Shirobai" literally means "motorcycle policeman".
Shiroba Ito - Accidental death
You there!!
こら！
He's managed to shake off the cop! He's getting away!
火口が白バイを振り切って逃走！
What's up with this guy?
なんて奴だ…
This is the Traffic Riot Police--
こちら交通機動隊…
T-The bike has collided with a truck! It's a complete wreck!
し…白バイがトラックに追突…大破！
A wreck?! An accidental death?
大破!!事故死…？
This is bad...
まずいですね
When Higuchi had his hand in his bag... did he manage to do something then?
火口はカバンの中に手を入れたが
その時何かしたのか…
More importantly, how did he manage to find out the name of that traffic cop?
いや、それより、白バイ隊員の名前をどうやって得たのがだ
Just like the second Kira, could he have known by just looking at him?
もしかすると第二のキラのように顔だけで…
Rem... a deal...
レム…取引……
No. If he can now kill knowing only the face, he should be able to kill Matsuda immediately, since he knows his face...
違う
顔だけで殺せるようになったのなら、
顔を知っている松田もすぐに殺せるはず
No. If he can now kill knowing only the face, he should be able to kill Matsuda immediately, since he knows his face...
どうなってる…
What's going on? But...
しかし…
Everyone! I believe that it'll be too dangerous to allow Higuchi to act any further!
皆さん！
火口をこれ以上を動かすのは危険だと考え、確保に移ります！
We're going ahead with his capture.
However, Higuchi is now able to kill just by looking at someone's face, similar to the second Kira.
しかし火口は第二のキラ同様、
「顔だけで殺せるキラ」になった！
We'll be making the arrest under that assumption!
その考えの元での確保です！
ワタリ、警察庁長官に繋いでください
Watari, put me through to the Director of the Police Department.
Yes.
はい
This is L.
L です
I've determined who Kira is.
キラをある個人に断定しました
He's currently driving a red Porsche 911 on National Highway Route 1 from Hibiya towards Shibuya.
現在、国道１号線、
日比谷から渋谷方面に向かっている、赤のポルシェ９１１
We'll be apprehending him ourselves, but I need you to inform your men not to approach that Porsche.
確保はこちらでしますので
そのポルシェに近付かぬよう、全警察官に通達願います
Father, after these commercials, it's time for the seventh part of the plan.
父さん、次のCM から第七対応だ
Understood.
わかった
Demegawa! We'll put our plan into motion during the next set of commercials.
出目川
次のCM で松井と司会者をマネキンに替え
Replace Matsuda and the Presenter with mannequins, and we'll use the audio we prepared to complete the facade.
用意したの音声で、いかにも放送は続いてるように見せる
Then leave the cameras to continue filming and evacuate everyone from the building.
そしてカメラを残して、全員撤収だ！
Well then, Yagami-kun. Shall we go too?
では夜神君、私達も行きますか
Yeah.
ああ
I'm sorry Misa-san, but I'm going to leave you immobilized for a while.
海砂さんはすみませんが
しばらく動けないようにしていてもらいます
ええっーー!!
What's all this?! Stop messing around!
なにこれ？
ふざけないで！
What's all this?! Stop messing around!
I'm surprised you can pilot a helicopter on top of everything else, Ryuuzaki...
ヘリの操縦までできるとは思わなかったよ、竜崎
It's simple.
勘です
Doesn't seem like Higuchi is heading towards Sakura TV. He's going in the wrong direction.
火口をさくらテレビに向かっていないな…方向が違う
Considering his route, he's heading towards Yotsuba Headquarters.
このルートだと、多分ヨツバ本社ですね
You're incredibly brave.
それはすごい勇気ですね
No, I only did what one would expect...
ええ、当然のことです
If only I can get back to the office and watch him on the surveillance tapes, I can kill him.
本社に行って、あいつの映った監視ビデオさえ見れば殺せる…
Weddy, did you manage to destroy everything regarding Matsuda-san at Yotsuba Headquarters?
ウエディ
ヨツバ本社の松田さんに関する全ての物、処分できてますね
Yes. Is he heading for the Headquarters?
はい
あいつ本社に向かってるの？
How convenient.
都合いいわね
This gives Mr. Yagami and me time to get to the TV station before him and set up an ambush.
先回りして、Mr. 夜神と局で待ち伏せる余裕ができるわ
Shit! It's not here!
くそっ…どこにもない！
No... it should be on the tape. It's been erased!
いや…このビデオなのに消されている…
Did he get in here and erase it himself?
奴がここに消しに来たのか？
Or is someone betraying me by helping him?
それとも、奴に手を貸し、裏切っている者が…
No, they would be arrested as well.
いや…そんな事したって同罪になるだけ
とにかく時間が…急がなくては…
Either way, I don't have much time. I've got to hurry!
さあいよいよ、発表の時間が迫ってきましたね
Finally, it's nearly time for the big announcement.
Yes. I really want to hurry up and get it off my chest.
はい、もう早く言ってしまいたいくらいの気持ちです
I understand how you feel, but for now, we're just going to take a quick break.
気持ちはわかりますが、ここで、一度CM を…
Damn it! The only thing left is to go to Sakura TV and kill him.
くそっ！…　もうさくらテレビに行って、やるしかない…
Father, it seems that Higuchi is finally heading towards Sakura TV.
父さん
いよいよ火口をさくらテレビに向かうようだ
He'll be there in less than 15 minutes. Are you okay?
十五分足らずで着く、大丈夫か？
I don't need my own son to worry about me.
息子に「大丈夫か？」などと言われたくない
I'm fine, Light.
大丈夫だ、月
Have you got anything more to add before you make the announcement?
もう発表前に、言いたい事はありませんか？
Let's see...
そうですね…
キラが捕まった後の事を、皆さんによく考えて欲しいと思えます
Everyone, think very carefully about what will happen once Kira has been caught.
Mr. Yagami, it's nearly time.
Mr. 夜神、いよいよね
やっぱりキラは悪ですね
After all, Kira is evil.
Yes...
ああ…
Here.
これ
ん？
Aiber doesn't like guns, so I'm the only one carrying a gun.
アイバーが銃が嫌いで、私しか持ってないから
I'm no longer a cop. I'm not allowed to carry one anymore.
私はもう警察官ではない、これを持つ事は許されない
You're not supposed to use yours in Japan either.
キミが日本で使う事もだ
You're so stubborn...
相変わらず堅いのね
Made it.
…間に合った！
Why is no one else here?
何故誰もいない…
Is this a precaution in case today's broadcast really is true?
今日の放送は、真実だから念のため、か…
Well, if there's no one around, it just makes this easier.
まあ、誰もいないならいないでやりやすい
We've arrived at Sakura TV.
さくらテレビに着きました
We're taking up our positions.
位置につきます
Let's go, Aiber.
行こう、アイバー
Okay, Mogi!
OK 、模木
We've received a lot of calls and faxes in support of your testimony.
今まさに、キラの正体を明かせるとする
勇気ある証言者であるあなたに
応援の電話、ファックスが、どんどん入っています
Even the studio is empty?
スタジオが中まで空…
But I still have to be aware of the camera positions.
しかし、テレビカメラの位置には気をつけなければ…
まことに申し訳ありませんが
We're very sorry, but due to various circumstances, we'll have to end this program.
都合により、この番組はここで終了させていただきます
What?!
何っ!?
Dolls?! It can't be!
人形…!!
まさか……
Hold it right there, Higuchi!
そこまでだ！火口！
Don't move!
動くな！
Give up.
観念するのね
T-This has gotta be some kind of mistake... I've arranged to meet Demegawa-san.
な…何か勘違いをしてませんか
私は出目川さんと打ち合わせたい事があって…
They're all wearing helmets... must be countermeasures against Kira.
メットをかぶっているという事は…キラ対策
In that case...
そうなると…
私はヨツバグループ開発室の者…
I'm from the Yotsuba Group's developmental labs... let me just find you my card...
今、名刺を…
Chief!
局長！
Aiber!
アイバー！
Damn it... I don't want to use one of these, but...
くそっ…　こんな物使いたくはないが
ちっ！
Higuchi's got a gun.
火口は拳銃を所持、局長が撃たれました…
The Chief has been shot. Higuchi managed to escape.
火口、逃走！
I'm fine... Sorry, Ryuuzaki...
大丈夫だ…
すまん、竜崎
If you hurry after him, you can still catch him.
すぐ追えばまだ捕まえられる
Hurry!
…急げ
This isn't good. He's escaped from Sakura TV.
まずい
さくらテレビから逃げられたぞ！
There's no choice.
仕方ありません
私達も直接確保に移ります
We've got to actively join this pursuit.
Watari, are you ready?
ワタリ、用意はいいですか？
Yes.
はい
Yagami-kun, please hold onto this for your own protection.
夜神君
これを護身用に持っていてください
Our opponent is Kira, after all.
相手はキラです
No... that's illegal in Japan.
いや、日本でそれは許されない
I'm sure Yagami-san said the exact same thing.
きっと…夜神さんも同じ事を言ったんでしょうね
Yeah...
ああ…
Damn...
ちっ…
He's driving all over the place!
なんて運転だ
Okay, go now!
見失うなよ
Okay.
OK
What the hell was that about?! I can only guess it was a trap...
さっきはどういう事だ…
罠だったとしか…
We take a break from our scheduled program to bring you the news.
ここで、番組を変更して、ニュースをお伝えします
The program stopped... but I wasn't the one who stopped it...
番組は止まったが、私が止めたのではない…
くっ、くそっ…
S-Shit... what's going on?!
一体…
What the--
なんだ？
So it was a trap after all!
…やはり罠だったんだ
All the patrol cars have tinted windows...
スモークを貼ったパトカーだと…
Have they secretly continued their Kira investigation?!
警察は、裏でしっかりとキラ対策を立てていたのか…!!
What's this? I thought I asked the police not to get involved.
何でしょう
警察には動かないよう、言ったんですが…
The only person who'd do this is...
こんな事をするのは…
Yes, that's right.
はい、そうですね
Damn it! There!
くそっ…こっちなら！
It ends here.
そこまでだ
Stay back! Don't come near me!
来るな!!
誰も来るなーーー!!
Guess it's over...
終わったな…
Yes... it is.
はい、そうですね
To be continued
このノートに名前を書かれた人間は死ぬ…
書かれた人間の顔が頭に入っていないと効果はない
故に、同姓同名の人物に一遍に効果は得られない